## DEAN

## CONTACT INFO

# SMART

- 07905962263
- deanssmart@gmail.com
- github.com/deanssmart

ENGINEER & FULL-STACK DEVELOPER OF Flat 110, The Milliners,

Flat 110, The Milliners
St Thomas Street
Bristol, UK

## **PROFILE**

Highly skilled, first class automotive engineer with over 8 year's industrial experience for luxury brands. Excellent communicator with strong leadership skills with experience working in crossfunctional teams with all levels of employees. Dedicated and passionate to succeed, with a flair for accuracy and detail.

Successfully completed the Develop-Me Full-Stack developer course and looking forward to showcasing my skills and competence in coding to deliver effective solutions to technical and creative challenges.

## SKILLS

### Software Engineering

Web Technologies:

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript (Vanilla & DOM), Object Oriented PHP.

Frameworks:

React/ Redux, Laravel

Tooling:

Git, GitHub, Gulp, npm, Vagrant, Dev Tools, VS Code, TDD, wireframing with Balsamiq

Server-side

MySQL, Database Migrations, APIs

Other languages

Self-taught basic C++ and visual basics.

### Mechanical Engineering

CAD

NX, VisMockup, VisVSA, CATIA

Analysis

STAR CCM, Phoenics, ANSYS, MATLAB and SIMULINK

## EXPERIENCE

### **Dyson Automotive Ltd**

Program Attribute Team Lead – Optical Quality | Oct 2017 – Feb 2020

Responsible for the full vehicle exterior optical quality attribute, specifically the dimensional quality. Effectively developed and implemented new processes that influenced design and engineering decisions, set targets and evaluated concepts.

- Created and managed the full vehicle exterior gap plan to describe every interface, working closely with multiple stakeholders to ensure design intent, engineering functionality and premium market quality targets were achieved.
- Utilised software skills in GapGun technology and SPC3d to introduce a new method of benchmarking Gap/Flush/Rad measurements to create a comprehensive database for future projects to maximise efficiencies.
- Established a strategy for the implementation of a Variation Analysis Department to function across the whole business analysing engineering datum strategy and tolerance assumptions.
- Professionally development skills through training on Siemens VSA software.

## Aston Martin Lagonda

Senior Design Engineer | Sept 2011 - Sept 2017

A key member of the DB11 convertible roof team, working cross-functionally whilst managing stakeholders and overseeing external suppliers throughout the whole production lifecycle from initial concept to final patented production released commodity. Collaborating with internal departments, such as body development, through prototype build, planning test procedures and designing rigs to mitigate against failures pre-defined from FMEA sessions.

- Assigned the role of body mechanisms lead during verification prototype build phase of DB11 Volante. Working closely with the launch team as a coordinator to track, assess and mitigate against build risks.
- Designed and implemented a companywide procedure for DB11; The
  engineering section book process for the whole vehicle aims to ensure;
  architecture, assemblies and components through every department align and
  work together.
- Effectively collaborated with a wide variety of departments to ensure projects
  were delivered on time and target following AMPCS (more recently MISSION) for
  numerous projects including: Vanquish Engine start bezel, DB11 AerobladeTM,
  DB11 Volante Wind deflector, Variable load divide and Convertible Roof.

## **EDUCATION**

### DevelopMe Coding Fellowship - Full Stack Software Development

Project driven bootcamp in software engineering using the web stack | Jun - Sept 2020

### University of Hertfordshire

Automotive Engineering (1st MEng) (1st BEng) | Sept 2006 - June 2011

### **Chislehurst and Sidcup Grammar School**

Art, Maths, Physics, Chemistry (AS), Drama (AS) | Sept 2003 – June 2005

## DEAN

# SMART

CONTACT INFO

- 07905962263
- deanssmart@gmail.com
- github.com/deanssmart

– ENGINEER & FULL-STACK DEVELOPER 💡 Flat 110, The Milliners,

Flat 110, The Milliners St Thomas Street Bristol, UK

## TRAINING

# Hamburg University of applied Sciences

Body Engineering Design Principles
Jan –April 2012

### SKILLS

### **Personal Attributes**

- Leadership
- Communication
- Teamworking & collaboration
- Attention to detail
- Creativity
- Interpersonal skills
- Organisation
- Initiative

### INTERESTS

### **Hobbies & Interests**

- Fine Art: painting and portraiture
- Team sports (Rugby)
- Science and technologies

## REFERENCES

Available upon request

## EXPERIENCE (Continued)

### Herbert Industrial Ltd, Herbert Group

Project Engineer | July 2008 - August 2009

Twelve-month industrial placement as part of Sandwich degree as a Project Engineer working closely with the operations manager, project managers and technical department. Gaining a complete overview of the sales order process from sales opportunity studies, through confirmation of machine specifications, completing CAD work, monitoring production build, testing & verification through to successful equipment installation

- Undertook pre-sales testing and feasibility studies into potential sales opportunities.
- Generated production plans and work instructions, ensuring the equipment's reliability and production build efficiencies.
- Continually monitored project schedules modifying and updating MS project Gantt charts to ensure critical paths were met and projects were completed punctually.
- Generated Production BOM's from confirmation quotations and self-generated detailed specifications, using appropriate CAD systems.
- Successfully managed and lead several critical investigations in order to improve product capability, learning valuable leadership and organisational skills

### Software Portfolio

URL: deanssmart.github.io/portfolio

### Frankenstyle

JS, React/Redux, HTML, CSS, JSX PHP, Laravel,

Interactive four player Pictionary style game where players take it in turns to draw and guess randomized words.

**URL**: deanssmart.github.io/frankenstyle **Code:** github.com/deanssmart/frankenstyle

### The Vet Practice

PHP, Laravel, Blade, MySQL, HTML, CSS RESTful API

A veterinary practice database app that allows tracking of owners and their pets with a one to many relationship and pet treatments with a many to many relationship.

**URL**: vet-practice.herokuapp.com

Code: github.com/deanssmart/the-vet-practice

### **TOURN**

JS, React/Redux, HTML, CSS, JSX

Tron(esque) themed app which randomly creates pairings for a tournament bracket from a list of names collected from the user.

**URL**: deanssmart.github.io/TOURN **Code:** github.com/deanssmart/TOURN